<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blogs on DAACS</title>
    <link>https://daacs.net/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blogs on DAACS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daacs.net/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS at 2022 AERA</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2022/04/2022-04-25-aera/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2022/04/2022-04-25-aera/</guid>
      <description>Efficacy of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills for Traditional-Age College Students Monday, April 25th, San Diego, CA
Abstract The purpose of this study was to examine the effects and predictive power of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) on student success. DAACS is a diagnostic assessment tool designed to measure college students’ reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning skills and provide them with feedback and resources to enhance their success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS Team Wins IES Grant to test the Efficacy of DAACS on Student Success</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2021-07-14-ies_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2021-07-14-ies_grant/</guid>
      <description>Examining the Efficacy, Predictive Power, and Cost Effectiveness of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills The CUNY School of Professional Studies (CUNY SPS) has been awarded a highly competitive and prestigious $3,789,074 million grant from the U.S. Department of Education’s Institute of Education Sciences (IES) to study the impact of online assessment tools on college students’ success.
CUNY SPS will lead a partnership with SUNY Albany, Rutgers University, SUNY Empire State College, and University of Maryland Global Campus (UMGC) to examine the efficacy, predictive power, and cost effectiveness of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS), a suite of technological and social supports designed to optimize student learning, on newly enrolled college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS at OLC Accelerate</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/11/2019-11-20-olc_accelerate/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/11/2019-11-20-olc_accelerate/</guid>
      <description>Using Diagnostic Assessment Data to Advance Student Success: Results from the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) Project Wednesday, November 20th, 1:15pm, Orlando, FL
Abstract The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) is a suite of open source, online assessments and supports (both technological and social) designed to optimize student learning. A study conducted at two online colleges suggest that DAACS is associated with increased student performance and accuracy of predictive student success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS at the Maryland Assessment Research Center Conference</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/11/2019-11-07-marc_conference/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/11/2019-11-07-marc_conference/</guid>
      <description>Using Diagnostic Assessment Data to Advance Student Success: Results from the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) Project **Thursday, November 7th, 2:45pm to 3:30pm, University of Maryland, College Park, MD **
More information here: https://education.umd.edu/research/centers/marc/workshops-and-conferences/2019-marc-conference</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS Receives StAR Award from University at Albany</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/05/2019-05-17-star_award/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/05/2019-05-17-star_award/</guid>
      <description>The DAACS team received a $48,500 Strategic Allocation of Resources (StAR) award from the University at Albany to implement DAACS at the University. Students enrolling beginning in 2020 will be an integral part the onboarding process. More information from the abstract:
 DAACS is a fully functioning, free, online suite of diagnostic assessments of college readiness, including reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning (https://daacs.net/). DAACS provides newly enrolled students with the information and resources needed to prepare for the academic rigors of college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dr Bryer to be panelist for World Future Forum</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-24-worldfutureforum/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-24-worldfutureforum/</guid>
      <description>Future Review Panel: Approaches to Studying Student Success in Higher Education Thursday, April 24, 11:25am to 12:10pm, Chicago
This panel will highlight the work that is published in Future Review, our publication. Two of the first authors to publish in this journal will discuss their work on student success. The panel features both quantitative and qualitative research, and highlights the different ways of conceptualizing student success in higher education. Panelists will also discuss how their research can be used by practitioners in higher education, and why they chose Future Review as a venue for their research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Educational Research Association</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-05-aera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-05-aera/</guid>
      <description>Efficacy of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Students on Multiple Success Indicators Authors: Jason Bryer; Angela M. Lui; Heidi L. Andrade; David W Franklin; Timothy J. Cleary
Abstract The purpose of this study is to examine the effects and predictive power of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) on student success. DAACS is a no-stakes, open-source, formative assessment tool designed to measure newly enrolled college students’ reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning (SRL) skills, and provide them with feedback and resources to enhance their functioning and success.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Council on Measurement in Education</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-05-ncme/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-05-ncme/</guid>
      <description>Relationship Between Intraclass Correlation and Percent Rater Agreement Authors: Jason Bryer; Guher Gorgun
Abstract Inter-rater reliability (IRR) is a critical component of establishing the reliability of measures when more than one rater is necessary. There are numerous IRR statistics available to researchers including percent rater agreement, Cohen&amp;rsquo;s Kappa, and several types of intraclass correlations (ICC). Several methodologists suggest using ICC over percent rater agreement (Hallgren, 2012; Koo &amp;amp; Li, 2016; McGraw &amp;amp; Wong, 1996; Shrout &amp;amp; Fleiss, 1979).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Validity Evidence of the Internal Structure of the DAACS Self-Regulated Learning Survey</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-01-futurereview/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/04/2019-04-01-futurereview/</guid>
      <description>Validity Evidence of the Internal Structure of the DAACS Self-Regulated Learning Survey Authors: Angela M. Lui, David Franklin Jr., Diana Akhmedjanova, Guher Gorgun, Jason Bryer, Heidi L. Andrade, and Timothy Cleary
Abstract The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) online system assesses newly enrolled college students’ skills in reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning, and provides individualized feedback and links to resources. The purpose of this study is to examine validity evidence regarding the internal structure of the DAACS Self-Regulated Learning (SRL) self-report survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>National Association of School Psychologists</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/02/2019-02-26-nasp/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/02/2019-02-26-nasp/</guid>
      <description>Improving Interventions: Development of the Implementer Perception of Intervention Survey Authors: Jacqueline Slemp, Devora Panish, Erica Pawlo, Timothy Cleary
Abstract The Implementer Perception of Intervention Survey (IPIS) was developed to evaluate academic support personnel’s perceptions of the usability, feasibility, and importance of an academic intervention for developmental, entry-level college students. Principal axis factoring of the IPIS yielded a two-factor structure. The factors were labeled perceived acceptability and perceived usability. Practitioners can adapt the IPIS for use in a variety of academic interventions and educational contexts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIG Writing Conference 2018</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/08/2018-08-30-sig-writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/08/2018-08-30-sig-writing/</guid>
      <description>Developing and Validating the DAACS Writing Assessment Authors: Heidi Andrade, Jason Bryer, and Robert Yagelski
Abstract This paper describes an ongoing project in which on-demand writing is used as part of a diagnostic evaluation of newly admitted college students. The authors will present preliminary evidence of the validity and reliability of human and machine scored essays and the usefulness of the feedback provided to students on their writing and their self-regulated learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Distance Teaching and Learning Conference</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/08/2018-08-09-dtandl/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/08/2018-08-09-dtandl/</guid>
      <description>Distance Teaching and Learning Conference Although the issues of placement exams impact most less selective or open enrollment colleges, the efficacy of DAACS as an alternative to traditional placement exams was conducted at two large online distance education colleges: Excelsior College and Western Governors University. DAACS is an assessment framework that provides students with a formative view of their skills in self-regulation, reading, writing, and math. For administrators, DAACS provides valuable information to inform personalized interventions and more accurate risk modeling.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>League for Innovation in the Community College</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/03/2018-03-18-league/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2018/03/2018-03-18-league/</guid>
      <description>Rethinking Placement Exams: Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills Abstract This session will introduce a new open source formative assessment developed as an alternative to tradition placement exams that measures self-regulated learning, reading, mathematics, and writing. Results from a pilot study conducted at two large online institutions will be discussed.
The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) addresses the issues with traditional placement exams and remediation programs by providing students with immediate, detailed, formative feedback.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northeast Education Research Association</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/10/2017-10-20-nera/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/10/2017-10-20-nera/</guid>
      <description>Development Of The Large Scale Diagnostic Assessments Of College Skills Authors: Jason Bryer, Excelsior College; Fusun Sahin, American Institutes for Research; Heidi Andrade, Angela Lui, Diana Akhmedjanova, &amp;amp; David Franklin, University at Albany, SUNY
The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS) is a technology-based, no-stakes diagnostic assessment system on academic and non-academic skills, with fast, actionable feedback. Development and piloting of these assessments at two online colleges is underway.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WNYT Forum 13</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/08/2017-08-06-wnyt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/08/2017-08-06-wnyt/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Bryer Discusses DAACS on News Channel 13&amp;rsquo;s Forum 13 Program  Source: WNYT Forum 13</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>