<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Award on DAACS</title>
    <link>https://daacs.net/tags/award/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Award on DAACS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daacs.net/tags/award/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS Team Wins IES Grant to test the Efficacy of DAACS on Student Success</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2021-07-14-ies_grant/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2021-07-14-ies_grant/</guid>
      <description>Examining the Efficacy, Predictive Power, and Cost Effectiveness of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills The CUNY School of Professional Studies (CUNY SPS) has been awarded a highly competitive and prestigious $3,789,074 million grant from the U.S. Department of Education’s Institute of Education Sciences (IES) to study the impact of online assessment tools on college students’ success.
CUNY SPS will lead a partnership with SUNY Albany, Rutgers University, SUNY Empire State College, and University of Maryland Global Campus (UMGC) to examine the efficacy, predictive power, and cost effectiveness of the Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS), a suite of technological and social supports designed to optimize student learning, on newly enrolled college students.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DAACS Receives StAR Award from University at Albany</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/05/2019-05-17-star_award/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2019/05/2019-05-17-star_award/</guid>
      <description>The DAACS team received a $48,500 Strategic Allocation of Resources (StAR) award from the University at Albany to implement DAACS at the University. Students enrolling beginning in 2020 will be an integral part the onboarding process. More information from the abstract:
 DAACS is a fully functioning, free, online suite of diagnostic assessments of college readiness, including reading, writing, mathematics, and self-regulated learning (https://daacs.net/). DAACS provides newly enrolled students with the information and resources needed to prepare for the academic rigors of college.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>