<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on DAACS</title>
    <link>https://daacs.net/categories/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on DAACS</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://daacs.net/categories/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA SSRL SIG 2025 Spring Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2025/03/2025-03-06-college-readiness-profile_ssrl-sig-news/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2025/03/2025-03-06-college-readiness-profile_ssrl-sig-news/</guid>
      <description>DAACS is featured on the Spring Newsletter by Studying and Self-Regulated Learning (SSRL) Special Interest Group (SIG) of American Educational Research Association (AERA) by Timothy J. Cleary, Elie ChingYen Yu, Jason Bryer

Our research offers an alternative approach to college readiness assessments and interpretation. Historically, college readiness assessments (e.g., SAT, placement exams) have focused primarily on students’ academic skills (e.g., reading, mathematics), while ignoring other aspects of thismultidimensional construct (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AERA SSRL SIG 2021 Summer Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2025-03-06-college-readiness-profile_ssrl-sig-news-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jul 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2021/07/2025-03-06-college-readiness-profile_ssrl-sig-news-copy/</guid>
      <description>DAACS is featured on the Summer Newsletter by Studying and Self-Regulated Learning (SSRL) Special Interest Group (SIG) of American Educational Research Association (AERA) by Elie ChingYen Yu, Angela Lui, David Franklin

The Diagnostic Assessment and Achievement of College Skills (DAACS; daacs.net) was a 5-year FIPSE grant-funded project (#P116F150077) led by principal investigators Drs. Jason Bryer1, Heidi Andrade2, and Timothy Cleary3. For this project, we designed a suite of open source, online assessments and supports (both technological and social) to optimize student success in college.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WNYT Forum 13</title>
      <link>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/08/2017-08-06-wnyt/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://daacs.net/blog/2017/08/2017-08-06-wnyt/</guid>
      <description>Dr. Bryer Discusses DAACS on News Channel 13&amp;rsquo;s Forum 13 Program  Source: WNYT Forum 13</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>